all right I really hope this works I
just did it and then there was no sound
so now I'm redoing it and I'm not gonna
cut out the first little bit hopefully
the sound just works and if not
fast-forward a little bit because I'm
the sound gets better when I cut it out
that might have been what made the sound
not work my tech skills aren't good
enough to get it back so I want to talk
today about what happens under
capitalism and communism and the
co-operative
when to decide how much of something
gets made what price to set it at and
what quality level to make it up so
under communism theoretically there is
no price the price is set at cost and
how much they create is how much is had
the central planning department thinks
is needed and they create it at the
lowest probably adequate quality so that
they can make enough for everyone and
make it and make it very simple so
everyone gets the same thing everyone
gets the same at the adequate quality
under because they're just asking how
much do we need the question asked under
supply and demands by the producer is
what price will maximize my profit what
price should I set it at because if I
set it too high people aren't going to
buy it I'm not going to make enough
profit and if I set it too low I don't
have enough of a profit margin to be
able to make enough profit so with that
in mind they also have to figure out how
much of something to make and guess how
much their customers are going to want
they don't want to make too few of them
because then they're gonna miss out on
sales that they would have gotten and
they don't want to make too many of them
because they don't want them sitting on
shelves taking up space having resources
both time and actual tangible resources
in them that they're never going to be
able to recoup if they never able to
sell them and then the customer the user
gets to decide will I buy it at this
price point so there's is more of a
yes-or-no answer like it's a hundred
dollars yeah okay I'll just spend that
they don't get to have a say besides yes
yes or no under the co-operative model
we are not having this friction between
the producer and the user because we are
the producer and the user and we're
instead asking
how many of these do we need to make to
bring the price down low and have the
quality be the highest so what that
means is we're asking directly the
person who's who's making the decision
the individual if it's at this price
point how much are you buying at this
price point as we get lower and lower
people want to buy more and more
accessory if it's set out that way
sometimes people like buying the
high-end ticket item because it's
prestige this isn't that because this is
we're making jars of pasta how many do
you want if it's five dollars how many
do you want if it's two dollars and then
we're making the quantity that brings
the most happiness so if we we have
enough people willing to if we can get
it down to two dollars and we have we
need 10 million people signed up then
then we need to get it down to 10
million and then so the individual is
going to be answering the question how
much am I going to buy at the price
point and what quality for that so if if
I would pay five dollars so it was
organic but only three dollars if it was
conventional I'm putting that into the
system and then the system is saying
okay well we have ten thousand people
that are interested but we can't make it
this low because we don't have a million
people interested so therefore the
lowest price point we can set it out
making it at ten thousand to break-even
is four dollars and all the we know
people have committed they've committed
to the four dollars so we can make it at
that price and then we make it at that
price and people have committed then
they're committed to buying and there
can be a rating system to know did this
person continually go through right so
when you sign up for a Kickstarter we
care that the person you're giving money
to is going to be giving them the money
and then they're making the product here
we're saying we're asking would you
commit to this you're not actually
putting the money in until the product
is ready to be made until we've already
made the price point decision and then
you're committed to putting that money
in in advance before it gets made so if
you don't then put the money in that's
going to be a mark against you in the
future if you're with compassion though
because if you committed to something
for ten thousand dollars and now your
finances to completely change because
you've lost your job or got cancer we
need a way for that to be evidence
versus I changed
reminds because nature mind affects
everyone else whereas we need to have
compassion that life circumstances do
change so whole point is to make a more
efficient system and a more more
happiness for everyone and under I do
think in this regard capitalism does
better than communism but we can do way
better because we can take away the
friction that comes between producer and
user and instead be both of those at the
same time and decide what quality are we
comfortable at do we wanted to have a
long shelf life and put preservatives in
it
or do we want it to be something you
have to consume within a week and make
it every week and we're asking people
what their actual values are and having
them commit to it doesn't mean you're
now committed to buying that pasta sauce
for the rest of your life it means
you're committed to buying that jar of
pasta sauce at that price taste it do
you like it do you want more and as we
can feed back in the system cuz I'd be a
ridiculous thing to do every time you
need to buy pasta you can we can see
well you'll go through pasta you use a
jar of it a week so that's the amount
that you would want is this the price
point that's okay like it doesn't mean
for every item you have to have that
conversation that would be ridiculous
but for the bigger ticket items like
bikes and you know big electronics then
that would be how we would manufacture
enough of them to make the demands and
we can have surplus built in so if we
know that 10 that if we built 10% extra
we would sell them and if we built 500
percent extra we wouldn't we can find
the algorithm that or the algorithm can
tell us how much to make in surplus that
isn't going to be a risk but is gonna
add happiness because then those 10% of
people get to have it without having
gone through this process and that is
today's video hopefully the sound worked
all right bye